hey everyone welcome back to the data
science interview question series
in this video we will be looking at the
impact of multicollinearity on logistic
regression
but before that please try to pause the
video and think about the solution
okay let's jump on to the solution but
before that
please hit the subscribe button and
press the bell icon so that you never
miss an update on an interesting
interview question
let's start off by defining the
co-linearity i have a data set
data frame a which has three different
features a b and c
and a can be related with b in this
manner which is a equals to g b plus h
where g and h can be any constant values
for example
a equals to 1.5 cross b plus 2
let's try to extend the same
collinearity to multicollinearity here
also we have three different features of
the data
a b and c but
instead of just one feature a can be
actually
correlated with more than one features
here
a equals to gb plus ic plus h
again g i and h can be any constant
values but how this can actually impact
the logistic radiation
since i have three features i will have
three different weights corresponding to
three different features
and let's say i consider the values
of the optimized speed from the training
which are
three four and five respectively let's
plug in this weight values into the
logistic regression equation
so we will get 3 x 1 plus 4 x 2 plus 5 x
let's write this on a fresh piece of
paper again
now let's because of the collinearity
what i'll get is x1 equals to 2x2 and
once i plug in the
x1 value into the original logistic
regression equation
i'll get 6x2 plus 4x2 plus 5x3
and when i sum them all becomes 10x2
plus 5x3
now for the original set of weights i
have 3 4 and 5
where w3 is the most important feature
because of the highest magnitude value
and for the modified weights w2 becomes
the most important feature
because it has the highest magnitude
value
because of the co-linearity the most
important features can actually change
arbitrarily
and but the accuracy still stays same
for for both the original and the
modified debates
let's summarize all the points remember
guys this is how you will be speaking in
an actual interview
collinearity can change the importance
of feature weights arbitrarily
which actually results in the compromise
of interpretability of model
as we have seen in the last example
where w3 has the highest importance
in original weights and as we plug in
the value of
x1 equals to 2x2 w2 has become the
highest important feature so we cannot
actually
interpret the model perfectly last but
not the least
it actually don't impact the accuracy of
the model
if you find this video helpful please
consider subscribing
also push the bell notification so that
you never miss an update for an
interesting interview question
who knows this might be your next
interview question
also if you have any suggestions for
other topics please let me know in the
comment section
and i'll see you in the next video